I haven't smelled tatami mats in a long time.
久し振りに嗅ぐ　畳の匂い
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
诸神微信公众号正式上线啦，搜索「诸神字幕组」添加关注吧
Huh?
あれ　ここどこだっけ
Where am I?
What happened last night?
確か　昨夜…
Do you remember nothing at all
from when you were transformed?
変身中の記憶は全くなしかい
What are you talking about?
何のことです
But your right hand's still there.
でもまだ右手に残ってる
Right hand?
右手？
It's been so long
久し振りだなー　天井
since I've slept under a roof.
なっなに　なに　なにっ
What?
What?!
Huh?
あ　あーはいはい　はい　出ます
Um, uhh.
Okay, I'm taking the call.
出ます出ます出ます
今出ます　すぐ出ます
I'll do it right now!
Right this second!
Which button am I supposed to push?
えー釦どれ　えっ　これ
Um.
This one? C'mon, hurry up.
Gosh, which one is it?
はい　ここでも…あーどれなんだか
H-Hello?!
もっ　もしもし
Good morning!
グッドモーニング
Oh, Dazai-san.
ああ　太宰さんですか
Today's another fine day.
今日もいい天気だねぇ　新しい寮のほうはどうだい
How's the new dorm?
Great, thank you.
おかげさまで　野宿に比べたら雲の上の宮殿のようです
Compared to sleeping outdoors, it's heavenly.
それはよかった
That's good to hear.
The change of clothes at your pillow
is a gift from everyone at the agency.
枕元の着替えは　探偵社のみんなからのプレゼントだ
Thank you so much for everything.
本当　何から何まで有り難う御座います
ところで　敦君　いきなり申し訳ないが…
By the way, Atsushi-kun,
I apologize for asking
this out of the blue,
but there's been an emergency.
実は緊急事態が発生したのだ
緊急事態？
An emergency?
Yes, there's no time to waste.
ああ　一刻を争うのだよ　直に指定の場所に来てくれたまえ
Please come to the specified
location immediately.
It's a crisis!
大変な事態だ　君だけが頼りだよ
Only you can help.
O-Okay, I understand.
はい　わかりました
そ
の
重
い
足
を
膝
前
へ
導
く
sono omoi ashi o hiza o mae ni michibiku
That feeling pulls your feet onward,
その重い足を膝を前へ導く
负
责
人
Maki
负责人
chikara nanda tte Go ahead to
Telling you to go ahead towards a new power.
力
は
何
だ
っ
て
Go
ahead
問
う
力は何だって Go ahead 問う
君
の
中
に
生
じ
る
衝
動
は
treasure
kimi no naka ni shoujiru shoudou wa Treasure
That impulse born within you is a treasure!
君の中に生じる衝動はtreasure
日
听
Cc.
长
田
Cris
翻
译
兰
樱
Naga
校
对
小
伍
江
本
物
か
偽
物
か
つ
れ
て
行
け
よ
honmon ka nisemono ka tsureteike yo
Whether it's real or fake, just take it along!
日听
Cc.
长田Cris
翻译
兰樱
Naga
校对
小伍
小江
本物か偽物か つれて行けよ
空
想
の
彼
方
ま
で
僕
の
中
怠
慢
よ
kuusou no kanata notte boku no mata mo taemai yo
Straddling the limits of this fantasy, my legs probably won't last,
空想の彼方まで 僕の中の怠慢よ
soredemo ii yo yume demo
But that's just fine, even if it's only a dream.
时
间
轴
阿
水
压
制
Coolkid
さ
ら
っ
て
も
い
よ
夢
で
も
时间轴
阿水
压制
Coolkid
さらってもいいよ 夢でも
todokisou de todokanai Make some noise
It seems within reach, but somehow too far off, so make some noise!
届
き
そ
う
で
届
か
な
い
make
some
noise
届きそうで届かない make some noise
空
虚
な
日
常
は
輝
き
出
す
の
か
kuukyo na nichijou wa kagayakidasu noka
Are these empty days gonna start shining bright?
空虚な日常は輝き出すのか
吐
き
出
す
よ
う
に
し
て
前
に
漕
げ
ば
hakidasu you ni shite mae ni mae ni kogeba
If we push on through like we're about to hurl,
吐き出すようにして前に前に漕げば
僕
ら
の
未
来
は
加
速
し
て
い
く
だ
ろ
う
bokura no mirai wa kasoku shiteyuku darou
I'm sure our future will start to pick up speed!
僕らの未来は加速していくだろう
今
こ
の
時
が
止
ま
る
と
し
て
も
ima kono toki ga tomaru to shitemo kono kokyuu made
Even if this moment in time becomes frozen,
今この時が止まるとしても
こ
の
呼
吸
ま
で
止
め
ら
れ
は
し
な
い
さ
この呼吸まで止められはしないさ
tomerare wa shinai sa kudaranai gohoubi mada?
There's no stopping this breath, so where's my worthless reward?
く
だ
ら
な
い
くだらない
ご
褒
美
ま
だ
？
ご褒美まだ？
Are you ready, Atsushi-kun?
用意はいいかね　敦君
Yes.
はい
First, when you leave the room,
make sure you close the door.
先ず部屋を出たら　ドアをちゃんと閉めて　後ろを見ろっ
Look behind you!
Behind me?
後ろ？
Um.
えーっと…
What's all this about?
これは何ですか
What do you think?
なんだと思う
Maybe I'm hallucinating this morning?
朝の幻覚？
はっずれー
Wrong!
まさか　敵の襲撃ですか
Is it an enemy attack?
Did you get caught in a trap?
罠に掛かったとか
I got in myself.
自分で入った
はぁ？
Well, you see,
いや　何ねぇ
I heard that there's a way to commit
suicide by getting stuck in an oil drum,
こうしてドラム缶に嵌まる自殺法があると聞いたものだから
so I decided to give it a shot.
Diagram
Securing
the feet
is the key.
Securing
the feet
is the key.
ちょいと試してみたのだよ
But now that I have,
ところが　この通り試してみると
苦しいばかりで　一向に死ねない
I'm just suffering without
actually being able to die.
Not to mention, now that I've wedged myself
in this deep, I can't get out on my own.
然もここまで嵌まると　自力では出られない
死にそう
I think I might die.
I see.
But it's a way to commit suicide,
でも自殺法なのですから
そのままそうしていればいずれ自殺できるのでは？
so you should be able to kill yourself
if you stay that way, right?
I like suicide,
私は自殺は好きだが　苦しいのも痛いのも嫌いなのだ　当然だろ
but I don't like suffering or pain!
Why would I?!
Also, I only learned this after the fact,
それに後でわかったことだが
I see.
なるほど
これは自殺法ではなくて　拷問法だったのだァー
but it wasn't a suicide method.
It was a torture method!
There.
My name is Nakajima Atsushi.
僕の名前は中島敦
Just the other day,
先日　無自覚なまま虎に変身して暴れていたところをこの人
I turned into a tiger and went on a blind rampage.
It was this man, Dazai-san, who helped me.
太宰さんに助けられた
While Dazai-san is this kind of person,
そして　太宰さんはこんな感じだけど
those people with supernatural powers
あの異能力集団　「武装探偵社」の一員だった
all belong to the Armed Detective Agency.
Nakajima Atsushi!
中島敦
You'll become one of us.
これより君は私達の仲間になる
今日から君は「武装探偵社」の一員だ
From this day forth, you'll be a
member of the Armed Detective Agency.
That was painful.
痛かった
I owe you one, Atsushi-kun.
助かったよ　敦君
Without you, I would've
snapped in half at the waist.
君がいなかったら　腰からポッキリ二つ折りになるところだった
Didn't you ask your other coworkers for help?
他の同僚の方に助けを求めなかったのですか
I called them, sure.
電話したよぉ　「死にそうなんだけど」って
I told them I was on death's door.
But then everyone was all like,
"Congratulations."
そしたらみーんな口を揃えて「御目出度う御座います」だってさ
どう思う
How's that make you feel?
でしょうね
I'm not surprised.
Jeez.
全く
Anyone gifted with supernatural powers
has something wrong with them inside.
異能力者って連中は皆　どこか心が歪だ
Gifted, huh?
異能力者…か
Dazai-san.
太宰さん
Everyone at the Armed Detective Agency...
the private investigators, that is,
武装探偵社の…所謂探偵の方達は矢っ張り皆さん異能力者…なんですよね
they're gifted, right?
Right, they're an armed force taking on antagonists
the police don't stand a chance against.
そう　警察でも歯が立たない敵を倒す武装集団だ
I don't stand a chance at
joining the agency, then.
矢っ張り僕は探偵社には入れません
You're gifted just fine.
君も立派な異能力者じゃないか
It's true that I have the supernatural
ability to turn into a tiger,
確かに　虎に変身するのは異能力ですが
but I have absolutely no control over it.
僕はその異能力を全く制御できません
I just transform blindly.
ただ無自覚に変身してしまうだけで
I can't will myself to
transform into a tiger.
自分の意志で虎になることはできないんです
So I don't think I'll be
of any use, even if I join.
だから僕が入っても何の役にも立てないと思います
I really appreciate the offer, though.
有り難いお話ですが　すいません
I'm sorry.
What's your plan, then?
これからどうする心算だい
I think I'll look for a job
I can actually handle.
何とか僕にできる仕事を探してみようと思います
Although I don't think it'll be easy to find.
そう簡単に見つかるとは思えませんが
I have an idea for a potential job.
君ができそうな仕事に心当たりがある
I can help you get it, if you'd like.
よければ斡旋してあげられるが？
Really?
本当ですか
Episode 2
A Certain Bomb
Thank you so much!
宜しくお願いします
We're going to meet the sponsor
who'll introduce you to the job.
これから向かうのは　その仕事を紹介してくれる保証人さんの処だよ
I'm sure he'll like you.
必ず君のことを気に入ると思う
What's the job?
その仕事って…
No point spoiling the fun.
着いてからのお楽しみ
Well, there may be a test of sorts.
まっ　ちょっとした試験はあるかも
えっ　試験？
Huh?
A test?
Atsushi-kun, can you write?
敦君　字ぃ書ける？
一応　読み書きくらいは…
I do know how to read and write.
なら大丈夫だよ
Then you'll be fine.
You'll be just fine, I'm sure.
君なら大丈夫だ　私が保証する
I guarantee it.
Thank you!
助かります
You'd better thank me!
感謝したまえ
私に任せておけば万事大丈夫
Just leave it to me,
and everything will be fine!
After all, I am Dazai,
何故なら　私は太宰
the one and only whom the agency trusts
社の信頼と民草の崇敬を一身に浴する男なのだから
and the populace adores!
There you are, Dazai!
こんな処に居ったか　太宰
You bandage-squandering machine!
この包帯無駄使い装置がァー
N-Nice nickname there,
Kunikida-kun.
Bandage
Squandering
Machine
?!!
That
stung
just a little.
く…国木田君　今の呼び名やるじゃないか
誰が社の信頼を一身に浴する男だっ
Who's the one and only
one the agency trusts, huh?
お前が浴びてるのは　文句と呪いと苦情の電話だ
You're the one
and only one
who we get complaints,
curses, and grievances about!
Huh?
Calls about
complaints,
curses...
and
grievances?
complaints,
curses...
and
grievances?
What?
えー　私がいつ苦情なんて受けたのさー
Since when did I
ever get a complaint?!
Call in August:
八月某日入電
"One of your employees has been
caught in an offshore fishing net."
御宅の社員さんが海岸の漁業網に引っ掛かってるんだけど
引き取ってくんない
"Can you come retrieve him?"
Call in September:
九月某日入電
"Some weirdo buried himself on my farm."
うちの畑に変な人が埋まっとったんじゃが　そちらの同僚さんかのう
"Could he be one of yours?"
そっ　そ…そ…そん…
Th—Th—Th—Th—Th—
Call in the same month:
同月某日入電
"Pay your tab, okay!?"
うちの飲み代の付け　ちゃんと払ってくださいね　半年分です
"All six months' worth!"
そんな莫迦な…
That's impossible.
Who knew you were so good at imitating
other people, Kunikida-kun?!
国木田君がこんなに物真似が上手いなんてーっ
You bastard!
貴様ァー　人を愚弄するのも大概にせんか
Stop ridiculing me!
I wonder if it's actually a good idea
この人に仕事の斡旋をしてもらって　本当に大丈夫なんだろうか
to have him help me find a job.
Oh, right!
おう　そうだ
I wasted a whole minute
dealing with this idiot.
太宰の莫迦を相手にして　一分も無駄にしてしまった
Let's hurry to the agency!
探偵社に急ぐぞ
なんで
Why?
緊急事態だ
We have an emergency!
A bomber's taken a hostage and
holed himself up in our office.
爆弾魔が人質を取って　探偵社に立て篭もった
A bomber?
爆弾魔？
Um.
あのう…
What?
なんだ　探偵社はこのビルの四階だが
The agency's on the fourth floor.
That's not what I wanted to ask.
いや　そういうことじゃなくて…
Let's take the stairs, just in case.
念の為に　階段で行こう
Excuse m—
あのですね
Quiet!
静かにっ
あっ　すいません
Oh, sorry.
Let's go, Atsushi-kun.
行くよ　敦君
What?
はい？
I can't...
嫌だ
I can't take it anymore...
もう嫌だ
全部お前らの所為だ　「武装探偵社」が悪いんだ
It's all your fault.
The Armed Detective Agency's fault.
Where's the President?
社長はどこだ
Bring the President!
早く社長を出せっ
If you don't,
でないと　爆弾でみんな吹き飛んで死んじゃうよ
I'll blow everyone to kingdom come.
A personal grudge?
怨恨か　面倒な型だね
That's inconvenient.
ああ
Yeah.
Why am I here?
僕は何故ここにいるんだ
The bomber seems pretty
furious at the agency.
犯人は余程　探偵社に怒り心頭らしい
I don't think I'll be of
any use. May I go now?
役に立ちそうもないので　帰っていいですか
We do attract a lot of ill will.
うちは色んな処から恨みを買うからねえ
You're ignoring me?
無視ですか
Besides, that's a high-grade explosive.
それにあれ　高性能爆薬だよ
If the bomber acts on his
threat and detonates it,
犯人の云う通り　あれが爆発したら
the whole floor's as good as gone.
このフロアぐらい吹き飛ぶね
そんな
Oh no.
爆弾に何か覆い被せれば
We may be able to mitigate the
force of the explosion somewhat,
if we can find something to cover the bomb,
ある程度は爆風を抑えられるかもしれないが
but given the circumstances...
この状況じゃあね
I can't believe he took a woman
as a hostage, the coward.
然も女性を人質に取るとは　卑劣な…
Who's the girl?
あの女の子は？
She's Naomi-chan, a part-time
office assistant.
彼女はナオミちゃん　バイトの事務員さんだ
バイトさん？
A part-timer!?
Then she's a completely innocent bystander!
それじゃ完全にとばっちりじゃないですか
What should we do?
どうする
Why don't we let him see the President?
会わせてあげたらぁ　社長に
殺そうとするに決まってるだろ
He'll try to kill the President!
We can't let the President walk
into a situation like that!
そんなところにむざむざと社長を出せるか
I'm glad he's out on a business trip.
出張中でよかった
Then there's only one method.
となると…
方法は一つ
Are they going to use their abilities?
異能力を使うのか
Huh?
Go, go.
ほれほれ～ほれ行け～
C'mon, go!
Hey.
おい
Calm down, boy.
落ち着け　少年
来るなァ　社長以外に用はない
Stay away!
I only want to see the President!
If you do anything funny, I'll blow this up!
妙な素振りを見せたら　吹き飛ばすよ
Okay.
わかった
I know who you are. You're Kunikida!
知ってるぞ　アンタは国木田だ
I bet you're trying to
make me let my guard down
ボクを油断させて　あの嫌味な「異能力」を使う心算だろ
and use that annoying ability of yours!
Well, fat chance.
そうはいかないぞ
Get up on the desk on all fours
机の上に四つん這いになり　両手を見える処に置け
and keep both hands where I can see them!
Huh?
ああ？
I-If you don't do as I say,
云う通りにしないと　みんな道連れだぞ
I'm taking you all down with me!
This isn't good.
まずいな
Because of his personal grudge against the agency,
探偵社に私怨を持つだけあって　奴は社員の顔と名前を把握している
he's done his research on all
the members' names and faces.
If I go, it'll only provoke him.
これでは社員の私が行っても　彼を刺激するだけだ
Hmm. What to do?
却説　どうしたものか
I just got a really bad feeling.
今なんか　猛烈に嫌な予感が…
A—tsu—shi—ku—
敦君ー
嫌です
A—tsu—shi—ku—
No.
まだ何も云ってないよ
I haven't even said anything.
I already know what you're going to say.
云われなくてもわかります
Listen, Atsushi-kun.
聞いてくれ　敦君
You're the only one here who's not a formal
member, and who the bomber won't know.
社員ではなく　犯人に面が割れていないのは君だけだ
But even if I were to go,
でも…
僕が行っても何もできませんよ
I wouldn't be able to do anything.
It'll be fine.
大丈夫
We just need you to distract
him for a short while.
少しの間　犯人の気を逸らしてくれればいい
We'll do the rest.
後は我々がやるから
Let me think.
そうだなー
Knowing you, how about you
put on an off-putting act
君なら相手の意表を突くような駄目人間の演技でもして
気を引くというのはどうだろう
as a worthless human being?
Here are some props.
はい　小道具
Trust me.
信用したまえ
Scuffles on this scale
この程度の揉事　我々武装探偵社にとっては
are child's play to the Armed
Detective Agency, Atsushi-kun.
朝飯前だよ　敦君
S—S—Stop!
や…や…やめなさーい
Wh—Wh—What could you possibly accomplish?
こ…こ…こんなことして何になるー
き…きっと親御さんも泣いてるよー
I—I bet this would make your parents sad!
なんだアンタ
Who the hell are you?!
Sorry!
ごめんなさい
Scary
You're not with the agency.
アンタ　探偵社の人間じゃないな
A—A—A—As you can tell,
みみ…み…見ての通り　とおりすがりの新聞配達です
I'm just a newspaper delivery boy
who happened to pass by!
And what's a delivery boy
got to do with any of this?
新聞配達の人が何の用だ
No matter how much you might hate them,
いくら憎いからって　人質とか爆弾とかよくないよ
you shouldn't take hostages or set off bombs.
I'm sure there's something to live for.
生きていればきっといいことがある
Like what?
いいことって
Huh?
Wait a minute...
Did
you
even
think
that
thought
through?
Did
you
even
think
that
thought
through?
だからいいことってなに
What's something to live for?!
T—
ち…
What?!
ち？
T—Tea—Tea on rice!
S... S... Sure,
that's true.
ち…
ちゃ…茶漬けが食える
T—Tea—Tea on rice!
You can eat a lot of tea on rice!
茶漬けが腹いっぱい食える
You can sleep somewhere
with a roof over your head!
天井がある処で寝られる
寝て起きたら朝が来る
When you go to sleep at night,
you can wake up to a new day!
当たり前のように朝が来る
And every day is a new day!
But,
でも…
if you blow up, neither you
nor I will see another new day,
爆発したら　君にも僕にも朝は来ない
because we'll be dead.
何故なら死んじゃうから
I know that!
そんなことわかってる
What?!
Um.
やめたほうがいいと思うけどなー
I think you should reconsider.
I mean, if you die,
だって死んじゃったら
死んじゃうんだよ
you're really dead!
I'm sure you might wish
you were dead sometimes,
そりゃあ　死にたくなることだってあると思うよ
but there are people who keep on
living, even if the going's tough.
でも辛くても生きてる人だって
ほら　例えば僕
Oh, people like me!
I have no family and no friends.
家族も友達もいなくて
孤児院さえ追い出され
I even got chased out of an orphanage,
行く場所も生きる希望もない
and I have nowhere to go,
and no hope for the future.
そのうえ虎に変身しちゃうし
Besides, I even turn into a tiger.
Yeah, that's right!
ああ　そうですよ
確かに僕はあなたの云う通り
It's true that, like you say,
とりたてて長所もなく誰が見ても社会のゴミだけど
I lack redeeming qualities,
and everyone'd agree that
I'm the scum of society.
そんでもヤケにならずに生きてるんだー
But I still manage keep on living
without going all postal about it!
Good job, Atsushi-kun.
いいぞ　敦君
You have acting like a worthless
human being down to an art form.
演技を超えた素晴らしい駄目人間振りだ
So why don't you toss that bomb aside,
だからそんな爆弾なんか捨てて
and we can look for jobs together?
一緒に仕事探そう
ね？
Okay?
いいや…ボクは別に仕事を探してるわけでは…
N-No, I'm not exactly looking for one.
You
already
forgot
you're
pre-
tending
to
deliver
news-
papers?
Now, Kunikida-kun.
今だ　国木田君
I know!
わかっている
Ability:
異能力
Doppo Poet
「独歩吟客」
Wire Gun!
鉄線銃
Crap—
しまっ
Get him, Kunikida-kun!
確保だ　国木田君
だからわかっとるわ
Like I already said, I know!
One down!
一丁あがり～
All right. Good job, everyone.
はいはい皆さん　お疲れ様ー
"One down," you say?
何が「一丁あがり～」だ
"Now!"? "Secure him!"?
「今だー」とか「確保ー」とか口で云ってるだけで
全然働いてないではないか
You're all talk and no action!
What choice was there?
それはしょうがないよ　だって国木田君は
You lost at rock-paper-scissors,
Kunikida-kun.
ジャンケンで負けたんだから
You bastard.
貴様…
Well, all's well that ends well, right?
まあまあ　事件は解決したのだから　細かいことはいいじゃないか
I've heard that if you're too neurotic,
you'll get a lot of wrinkles
あまり神経質になりすぎると　皺が増えて　老化が急速に進むそうだよ
and you start to age faster.
Is that true?
それは本当か
ほら　メモメモ
Go on, take notes.
"If you're too neurotic.
神経質すぎると　老化が急速…
you start aging faste—"
嘘だけど
I'm messing with you.
Bastard!
貴様　人を愚弄するのもいい加減にせんか
Stop ridiculing me!
お前もな
All of you!
Crap!
しまった
莫迦にしやがって
Stop making fun of me!
I swear, anyone gifted with supernatural powers
has something wrong with them inside.
本当　異能力者って奴らはどこか心が歪だ
Thirty seconds left until detonation!?
後三十秒で爆発？
小僧
Hey, brat!
No way!
させるか
Kunikida-san!
国木田さん
What should I do?
どうする
We may be able to mitigate the
force of the explosion somewhat
爆弾に何か覆い被せれば　ある程度は抑えられるだろうけど
if we can find something
to cover the bomb.
Something to cover the bomb.
何か被せるもの…
Something!?
何か　何かないか
Anything!?
Atsushi-kun!
敦君
What?
Huh?
あれ　僕は何をやってるんだ
What am I doing?
Idiot!
莫迦っ
小僧
Brat!
Jeez.
やれやれ
I figured he was stupid,
but I didn't know how stupid.
莫迦とは思っていたが　これほどとは
He has the talent to become a suicide maniac.
彼には自殺嗜癖の才能があるよ
そうは思わないかい　谷崎君
Wouldn't you agree, Tanizaki-kun?
Sorry.
ごめんねー　大丈夫だった？
Are you okay?
Huh?
Aw, brother!
お兄様～
Are you all right?!
大丈夫でしたかー
What?
Tanizaki
Junichirou
Ability:
Light Snow
You were so wonderful as a villain!
悪いお兄様もすっごく素敵でしたわ
His
Younger Sister
Tanizaki
Naomi
縛られて　脅されて　私もうたまりませんでした
I had the time of my life
being tied up and threatened!
Please continue where we
left off once we get home.
家に帰ったら　続きをしてくださいますね
So the part-time worker was
in on it with everyone, too?
バイトさんもぐるってことですか
Brat, you should blame Dazai.
小僧　恨むなら太宰を恨め
Barring that, blame yourself for choosing
the wrong person to help you find a job!
さもなくば　仕事斡旋人を間違えた己を恨め
Then is this the job?
てことはこれって
I told you there was a test involved.
言っただろう　ちょっとした試験があるって
As in, an entrance exam?
つまり　入社試験？
その通りだ
That's right.
The exam has been completed
without much ado, President.
試験のほうは滞りなく終了しました　社長
I see.
President?
社長？
Since Dazai said there
was a capable young man,
そこの太宰めが「有能なる若者がいる」と云う故
Fukuzawa
Yukichi
President
of the
Armed
Detective
Agency
Ability:
All Men Are
Created Equal
President
of the
Armed
Detective
Agency
Ability:
All Men Are
Created Equal
I had him test your mettle.
その魂の真贋　試させてもらった
Well, I recommended you for hire,
いやね
君を社員に推薦したのだけれど　如何せん君は区の災害指定猛獣だ
but since you've been designated
a major threat by the ward,
there was disagreement among us as
to whether we should take you in.
保護すべきか否か　社内で揉めてね
But Dazai said...
だが太宰が云ったのだ
President.
社長
Suppose the most gifted person
in the world appeared before you,
社長はもしここに世界一強い異能力者が現れたら　雇いますか
would you hire him?
Power doesn't make you
a member of the agency.
そのことが探偵社員たる根拠とはなりえない
That's why I recommend him.
だから私は彼を推すんです
So, President, what is your decision?
それで社長　どのようなご判断を
I'll let Dazai decide.
太宰に一任する
You can trust me.
お任せください
W-Wait a minute, Dazai-san.
ちょ…ちょっと待ってください　太宰さん
So the job you meant to
introduce me for was...
それじゃあ僕に紹介する仕事って
You apparently passed the test.
合格だそうだよ
Welcome to the Armed Detective Agency,
Nakajima Atsushi-kun.
武装探偵社にようこそ　中島敦君
おっととと
Congratulations!
御目出度う御座いま～す
I'm glad I was able to help.
お役に立ててよかったです
いやいやいや
Oh, please, no.
I can't possibly join a workplace
as violent and reckless as this.
こんな無茶で物騒な職場　僕には無理ですよ
Not just anyone would use their body
to shield a bomb to save everyone.
皆を助ける為に爆弾に覆い被さるなんて
中々できることじゃない
そうですよ　ナオミ感動しちゃいました
That's right. I was really impressed!
You'll be fine.
君なら大丈夫だ
But...
でも
So, President, do you actually
want him to join the agency, then?
Secretary
Haruno Kirako
結局社長は彼に探偵社に入ってほしいというお考えなのですか
Oh, a tea leaf's standing straight up.
茶柱が立ってる
I think something good
will happen, President.
いいことがありそうですね　社長
Ouch.
熱っ
Still, well,
でも　まあ
if you still refuse, we can't force you.
君が断るなら無理強いはできない
But then, I can't help but
worry for your future.
しかしそうなると　私は君の今後が心配でならない
We'll need you to vacate the company dorm.
先ずは社員寮を引き払わなくてはならなくなるし
You don't really have any special skills,
君のようにこれといった特技もなく
然も友達も知り合いもいない者が仕事を探すのはさぞかし大変だ
nor do you have friends or know anyone.
That'd make finding a job very difficult.
Besides, you're a wanted tiger.
それに君はお尋ね者の虎だからな
Should anyone learn of that,
それが知れたら　どんな仕事もよくて首
at best you'd get fired from your job.
At worst, you'd be captured and shot dead.
悪ければ捕まって射殺だろうなー
しゃ…射殺
Sh-Shot dead?
Now, if you were with this agency,
この探偵社なら
it'd be a different story.
話は別だけど
Th-Then that means...
そっ　それってつまり
We look forward to working
with you, Atsushi-san.
よろしくお願いしますわ　敦さん
ね　お兄様ー
Don't we, brother?
Follow the rules, brat.
規則は守れよ　小僧
Well, now that's been settled.
じゃあ　そういうことで
You've got to be kidding me.
そんなー
僕が僕でいられる　理由を探していた
boku ga boku de irareru
I was searching for the reason
riyuu o sagashiteita
why I'm able to stay as I am.
あなたの胸の中で　生きている僕がいるのならば
anata no mune no naka de
If there's a version of me
ikiteiru boku ga iru no naraba
that exists in your heart,
kurayami mo nagai sakamichi mo
Then even if darkness looms on this rocky road,
暗闇も長い坂道も　越えて行けるような僕になれるはず
koeteikeru you na boku ni nareru hazu
I'll be able to find the way to the new me.
それぞれに今を歩いてる僕らが笑えるように
sorezore ni ima o aruiteru bokura ga waraeru you ni
So that we can keep smiling in our own moments,
ikiteiru imi o tashikameainagara susumeru you ni
So that we can explore the meaning of life together,
生きている意味を確かめ合いながら進めるように
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
あなたがあなたでいれるように
anata ga anata de ireru you ni
So that you can stay how you are.
kanashimi ni kurete, anata no namida ga koboreru toki
Whenever you're overcome by grief, and tears flow,
悲しみに暮れてあなたの涙がこぼれる時
寂しさに溢れて心がしぼんでく時
samishisa ni afureta kokoro ga shibondeku toki
Whenever your heard floods with loneliness and you waste away,
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
僕の名前を呼んでくれたみたいに
boku no namae o yondekureta mitai ni
Just as you once called out mine.
The weretiger has been found.
人虎が見つかったそうです
Episode 3
Yokohama Gangster Paradise